Guide to the Theodore Martindale Purdy Photographs and Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Theodore Martindale Purdy photographs and papers
1883-1931
MS 1994
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
(13 boxes)
This collection consists of photograph albums, maps, diaries and other materials documenting the worldwide travels of Theodore Martindale Purdy from 1883 to 1931.
Purdy, Theodore Martindale, 1862-1944
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Peter Van Dyk Berg, 2013.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as received from the donor.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of photograph albums, maps, diaries and other materials documenting the worldwide travels of Theodore Martindale Purdy from 1883 to 1931. The photograph albums form the bulk of the collection, and they richly document the landscapes, people, and cultures of the places Purdy visited during his travels, particularly Northern Africa, East Asia, Southeast Asia, and South Asia. There are also a small number of photographs documenting his travels in Europe, the United States, and Canada. Accompanying the photographs are Purdy's travel journals, sketchbooks, annotated travel maps and guides, postcards, and other materials produced or collected during his many trips abroad. Additionally, the travel diary in box 12, folder 4, includes many clippings of the travel dispatches that Purdy wrote for the New York Mail and Express.
Biographical / Historical
Theodore Martindale Purdy (1862-1944) was a resident of Short Hills, New Jersey, and between the years 1883-1931, he traveled extensively around the globe. During this time, Purdy worked as a correspondent for the New York Mail and Express, writing periodic dispatches from the locations to which he traveled.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Travelers -- United States; Africa -- Description and travel; East Asia -- Description and travel; Europe -- Description and travel; South Asia -- Description and travel; Southeast Asia -- Description and travel; Photographic postcards; Photographs; Travel journals; Purdy, Theodore Martindale, 1862-1944
- Inventory
  - Photographs
    - Albums
      - England, Holland, Switzerland, Italy, 1883-1884 (Box 1)
      - Burma, Java, Siam, China, 1889-1891 (Box 2)
      - Egypt, Ceylon, India, 1889-1891 (Box 3)
      - Gibraltar, Morocco, Tunisia, Greece, Egypt, Turkey, 1889-1891 (Box 4)
      - Great Britain, Switzerland, Italy, Germany, United States, 1889-1891 (Box 5)
      - Morocco, Algeria, Tunisia, Egypt, Greece, Italy, France, Ceylon, Singapore, China, Japan, 1890 (Box 6)
      - India, Japan, 1894 (Box 7)
      - Japan, 1895-1900 (Box 8)
      - Japan, Canada, 1895-1900 (Box 9)
      - Japan, Circa 1900 (Box 10)
    - Loose photographs, Circa 1890-1900 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - Passports, 1930-1931 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Postcards, Circa 1890-1930 (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
  - Ship passenger lists and routes, 1892-1929 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbooks, 1883-1892 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
  - Travel diaries, 1890-1894 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
  - Travel guides, 1883, 1894 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Travel maps, 1883-1901 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Travel scrapbook, 1883-1884 (Box 13)